C.J. Bates Company Records 2000.0076
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
C.J. Bates Company Records
1817-1980
2000.0076
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
132.0 Linear feet
Founded by Carlton J. Bates (1848-1941) in 1907, the C.J. Bates Company manufactured manicure sets, crochet hooks, and knitting needles in Chester, Connecticut.
Bates, C.J.
History
Founded by Carlton J. Bates ( 1848-1941 ) in 1907, the C.J. Bates Company manufactured manicure sets, crochet hooks, and knitting needles in Chester, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of financial ledgers, purchase books, share certificates, and account summaries.
Organization
Ledgers are arranged by type and then chronologically.
Acquisition Information
Donated to Archives & Special Collections in August 2000 by the Chester Historical Society.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut business records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
C.J. Bates & Son.; Chester (Conn.); Connecticut; Correspondence; Financial Records
- Ledgers, 1817-1980
  - Adkins Printing Company, 1915 (Box 1)
  - Book of Accounts, 1917 December (Box 2)
  - Capital Accounts, 1916-1938 (Box 3)
  - Cash Books
    - 1894 December - 1897 March (Box 4)
    - 1888 August - 1891 December (Box 5)
    - 1918 March - 1920 February (Box 6)
    - 1919 January - September (Box 7)
    - 1924 October - 1930 March (Box 8)
    - 1927 March - 1928 May (Box 9)
    - 1928 May - 1929 July (Box 10)
    - 1930 April - 1941 May (Box 11)
    - 1935 November - 1936 November (Box 12)
    - 1936 December - 1937 November (Box 13)
    - 1937 November - 1938 November (Box 14)
    - 1938 November - 1939 October (Box 15)
    - 1939 November - 1940 September (Box 16)
    - 1940 September - 1941 January (Box 17)
    - 1941 June - 1942 March (Box 18)
    - 1942 March - 1943 March (Box 19)
    - 1943 March - 1944 January (Box 20)
    - 1944 January - October (Box 21)
    - 1944 October - 1945 March (Box 22)
  - Cash Disbursements
    - 1946-1947 (Box 23)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 24)
    - 1960 September - 1962 April (Box 25)
    - 1963 May - 1965 April (Box 26)
  - Cash Receipts, 1946 July - 1947 July (Box 27)
  - Cash Receipts, 1947 May - December (Box 28)
  - Chastar Trust Company, 1914 October - 1915 January (Box 29)
  - Chester Trust Company, 1959-1961 (Box 30)
  - Chister Connecticut, 1915 January - 1916 July (Box 31)
  - Dexter Exhibit, 1869-1874 (Box 32)
  - General Ledger
    - 1914 August - December (Box 33)
    - 1915 January - July (Box 34)
    - 1915 January - October (Box 35)
    - 1916 October - 1918 March (Box 36)
    - 1917 February - May (Box 37)
    - 1917 January - 1919 December (Box 38)
    - 1918 March - August (Box 39)
    - 1918 September - 1919 June (Box 40)
    - 1920 July - 1922 February (Box 41)
    - 1924 June - 1925 September (Box 42)
    - 1927 March - 1928 February (Box 43)
    - 1929 July - 1930 August (Box 44)
    - 1931 September - 1933 March (Box 45)
    - 1934 October - 1935 November (Box 46)
    - 1938 May - October (Box 47)
    - 1939 February - August (Box 48)
    - 1939 November - 1940 July (Box 49)
    - 1940 July - 1941 January (Box 50)
    - 1941 January - 1941 August (Box 51)
    - 1941 November - 1942 March (Box 52)
    - 1942 March - August (Box 53)
    - 1942 May - August (Box 54)
    - 1942 August - December (Box 55)
    - 1945-1961 (Box 56)
    - 1947 October - 1949 August (Box 57)
    - 1947-1969 (Box 58)
    - 1967 May - 1980 January (Box 59)
  - Index A-H, 1921-1946 (Box 60)
  - Index I-Z, 1921-1966 (Box 61)
  - Journal
    - 1920 August - 1922 December (Box 62)
    - 1929 February - 1936 June (Box 63)
    - 1936 July - 1941 August (Box 64)
    - 1941 September - 1948 December (Box 65)
    - 1945 June - 1946 April (Box 66)
    - 1952-1954 (Box 67)
    - 1955 January - 1956 December (Box 68)
  - Materials, Supplies, (effective June 1941), 1947-1951 (Box 69)
  - Purchase Books
    - 1916 April - 1917 January (Box 70)
    - 1917 (Box 71)
    - 1917 November - 1918 September (Box 72)
  - Purchase Register, 1917 November - 1919 October (Box 73)
  - Puritan Manicure Case Company, Inc., 1817 December - 1920 February (Box 74)
  - Sales Analysis by Territories, 1937 January -June (Box 75)
  - Sales Analysis by Territories, 1937 June -November (Box 76)
  - Shares of Stock, 1917 December (Box 77)
  - Trial Balance
    - 1915 April - 1919 December (Box 78)
    - 1919-1921 (Box 79)
    - 1924 December - 1928 December (Box 80)
    - 1927 December - 1932 December (Box 81)
    - 1932 December - 1943 December (Box 82)
    - 1937-1941 (Box 83)
    - 1942 January - 1945 December (Box 84)
  - Voucher Register
    - 1924 October - 1933 March (Box 85)
    - 1932 September - 1934 October (Box 86)
    - 1934 October - 1936 April (Box 87)
    - 1936 April - 1937 September (Box 88)
    - 1937 October - 1939 May (Box 89)
    - 1939 May - 1940 November (Box 90)
    - 1940 November - 1942 May (Box 91)
    - 1944 August - 1946 May (Box 92)
  - Unidentified Ledgers
    - 1892 July - 1902 January (Box 93)
    - 1914 April - September (Box 94)
    - 1914 April - December (Box 95)
    - 1914 September - 1915 January (Box 96)
    - 1914 July - 1921 July (Box 97)
    - 1915 October - 1916 July (Box 98)
    - 1916 January - 1918 October (Box 99)
    - 1916 March - 1918 May (Box 100)
    - 1916 August - 1918 March (Box 101)
    - 1916 August - 1917 May (Box 102)
    - 1917 June - 1918 March (Box 103)
    - 1917 November - 1919 December (Box 104)
    - 1918 March - 1919 January (Box 105)
    - 1918 March - 1920 August (Box 106)
    - 1919 September - 1920 May (Box 107)
    - 1923 January - 1929 January (Box 108)
    - 1923 April - 1924 June (Box 109)
    - 1925 March - 1927 March (Box 110)
    - 1930 August - 1931 September (Box 111)
    - 1931-1945 (Box 112)
    - 1933 March - 1934 September (Box 113)
    - 1937 October - December (Box 114)
    - 1938 October - 1939 March (Box 115)
    - 1939 August - November (Box 116)
    - 1941 (Box 117)
    - 1942 (Box 118)
    - 1942 January - 1947 November (Box 119)
    - 1945 June - 1946 July (Box 120)
    - 1947 December - 1948 June (Box 121)
    - 1948 January - June (Box 122)
    - 1949 (Box 123)
    - 19?? November - 19?? May (Box 129)
  - Undated Ledgers
    - General Ledger (Box 124)
    - General Ledger (Box 125)
    - General Ledger (Box 126)
    - General Ledger (Box 127)
    - General Ledger (Box 128)
    - Order Register: Boxwood sticks and Birch- Plain White Celluloid (Box 130)
    - Order Register: Boxwood sticks and Birch- Guilford (Box 131)
    - Order Register: Boxwood sticks and Birch- Scissors (Box 132)